{
    "id": "e40ed38a2c594e2dbd846d412f3fc930",
    "title": "Agreement Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "41509d1963604ecca00088afb6b20c17",
            "title": "Agreement Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Vermin ………………….. our property and carry disease.",
                    "description": "Though vermin is singular in form, it is always used as a plural noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "destroy",
                        "destroys",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Whose cattle ……………………?",
                    "description": "Though cattle is singular in form, it is always used as a plural noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is this",
                        "are this",
                        "are these"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "His means ………………….. small, but he has no debt.",
                    "description": "When means is used with the meaning of wealth, it is always plural.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "are",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "A new means of communication ……………………….. invented in the 19th century.",
                    "description": "Both the singular and the plural of means end in –s.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "were",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I bought two ………………….. mangoes.",
                    "description": "When dozen is used after a number, it does not have a plural form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "dozen",
                        "dozens",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Man is the only animal that …………………….. fire.",
                    "description": "Here the antecedent of the relative pronoun is a singular noun (animal) and hence we use the singular verb uses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "use",
                        "uses",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Hunting tigers ……………………… a favorite sport in this country.",
                    "description": "Here the subject is the gerund phrase hunting tigers. It is singular.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "are",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "There ……………………. little hope of his recovery.",
                    "description": "Hope is a singular noun hence we use is.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "are",
                        "has"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Every one of these chairs ……………………. broken.",
                    "description": "We use a singular verb after every one.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "are",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He visits us every ……………………….",
                    "description": "We use a singular noun after every.",
                    "answers": [
                        "week",
                        "weeks",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He visits us every three ………………….",
                    "description": "A plural noun is used after every + numeral.",
                    "answers": [
                        "day",
                        "days",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "A house divided against …………………… cannot stand.",
                    "description": "Here the subject and the object refer to the same thing and hence we use the reflexive pronoun itself. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "itself",
                        "it",
                        "that",
                        "themselves"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}